

### CONTACT

mngmay@gmail.com

(206) 979 5145

www.linkedin.com/in/mngmay

Seattle, WA, USA

### **EDUCATION**

### **USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN**

2021 - Present

Career Foundry, Remote

# AWS CERTIFIED CLOUD PRACTITIONER

2020 - 2023

# COMPUTER SCIENCE & SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

2019

Lambda School (BloomTech), Remote

# BACHELOR OF ARTS: COMMUNICATIONS & CHINESE

University of Washington, Seattle

## **VOLUNTEER**

### **WORLD IA DAY LA**

www.worldiaday.org

IAC

www.theiaconference.com

## **PAWS ANIMAL SHELTER**

www.paws.org

# **MAY NG**

# Human Centric Problem Solver

### **ABOUT**

May is a life long learner who applies her background in technology and business to blend technical expertise with empathy in order to craft human-friendly experiences. She is actively learning and practicing various UX techniques to serve the community in her current role as a UX Apprentice at DIA Design Guild.

### **SKILLS**

Generative & Evaluative Research
Competitive Analysis
Usability Testing
Affinity Diagramming
Jobs to be Done
Recruiting & Interviewing

Figma
Google Analytics
HTML / CSS / Javascript
React / Next / Vue
Microsoft Office Suite / G Suite
Slack / Teams / Zoom

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **UX APPRENTICE**

DIA Design Guild (Remote) | Jan 2022- Present

- Design, propose, and implement plans using methods in user research, information architecture, content strategy, wireframes and prototypes.
- Collaborate with industry leaders to foster a growing UX community.

### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Academic Analytics (Remote) | Sept 2020 - Sept 2021

Technology: React, Next, Vue, Node, Go, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS, Docker

- Quickly learned and adapted to new technology to build R&D application prototypes from scratch.
- Utilized agile methodologies and collaborated with cross functional teams.
- Presented to executive stakeholders on product research, product features and advise on product direction.

### **CUSTOMER & DATA SPECIALIST - CONTRACTS**

Robert Half partnered with Convoy and Expeditors | April 2018 - May 2019

- Processed high volume of requests while meeting strict KPIs; reduced team backlog by 90% within 3 months.
- Advised developer teams on product direction based on customer feedback, end user process flows, and platform user testing.

### **HR SPECIALIST**

ChemPoint.com | Nov 2012 - Mar 2018

- Created welcoming and safe space for employees and candidates by expressing empathy, willingness to help, and follow up to ensure needs are met.
- Led full cycle recruitment for internship and entry-level programs including sourcing, coordinating, interviewing, and on/off-boarding.
- Designed, audited, streamlined and documented business processes.
- Built and presented HR metric reports to executive leaders.